The next algorithm I would like to show you is called Hybrid A*.
我将向大家展示的下一个算法称为 混合 A* 算法
To introduce you to Hybrid A*,
为了介绍此算法
I would like to share your video that Sebastian recorded for another class.
我先和大家分享一个视频 这是 Sebastian 为另一个课程录制的
Afterwards, I'm going to ask you the same question
然后 我会问大家一些问题
about Hybrid A* that you just answered about A*.
这些问题和前面有关 A* 算法的问题相同
So let's talk about robot path planning or robot motion planning.
那么 现在我们就开始讨论有关机器人路径规划或者机器人运动规划的问题
Where just a rich field in itself and I
这个领域涉及内容甚广
can't give you a complete survey of all the items involved.
我不可能讲到所有内容
But one of the key differences to the planning as
但是 与前面我们讲规划的时候不同
we talked about before is that now the word is continuous.
现在 我们强调的一个关键词是 连续性
So for example, we've read about A* in which we discretize the world.
例如 在我们讲解 A* 时 我们是将世界离散化的
You might have a goal location,
那里也许有一个目标位置 一些障碍物
you might have obstacles and then A*,
然后通过运行 A*
a valid action sequence might look like this.
会生成一个有效的动作序列 看起来类似这样
And even though this is a valid solution to the planning problem,
尽管这是一个规划问题的有效解
a car can't really follow these discrete choices.
实际上 一辆车是不可能沿着这些离散路径行进的
There's a number of very sharp turns over here
因为 这里有一些特别急的转弯
that are just irreconcilable with the motion of a car.
对于一辆车而言 这种动作是不可行的
So the fundamental problem here is A* is
所以这里的根本问题是
discrete whereas the robotic world is continuous.
A* 是离散的 而机器人世界需要连续性
So the question arises,
这就产生一个问题
is there version of A* that can deal with the continuous nature
是否有某种 A* 算法可以解决连续性问题
and give us probably executable paths?
并有可能给出实际可行的路径？
This is a big big question in robot motion planning.
在机器人运动规划领域 这是一个极其重要的问题
And let me just discuss it for this one example and show you
我会通过这个例子来讨论一下上述问题
what we've done to solve this problem with a duff probing challenge.
并给大家展示一下我们是如何通过一个达夫探查来解决此问题的
So the key to solving this with A* has to do with a state transition function.
使用 A* 解决此问题的关键在于利用一个状态转换函数
Suppose we are in a cell like this and you play a sequence
假设我们在这样的一个单元格内
of very small steps simulations using our continuous math from before,
然后大家使用我们先前的连续性数学算法运行一些列小步进模拟
then a state over here might find
然后 这里的一个状态或许会发现
itself right here in the corner of the next discrete state.
它自己在下一个离散状态的角落里
Instead of assigning this just to the grid cell,
混合 A*算法不会把这些值赋予单元格
an algorithm called Hybrid A* memorizes the exact X prime Y prime and theta
它会记忆 X’ Y’ 以及 theta'
prime and associate it with
当首次扩展到这个单元格时
the grid cell over here the first time the grid cell is expanded.
它会把这些值和这个单元格关联起来
Then when expanding from the cell,
然后 当从这个单元格扩展时
it uses a specific starting point over here to figure out what the next cell might be.
它使用一个这里特定的开始点来算出下一个单元格也许是什么
Now, it might happen that the same cell we used to get in A* maybe from over
现在 很可能发生的事情是 在 A* 算法中 从这里出发
here going into a different continuous polymerization of X, Y and theta,
经过的同一单元格可能会算出不同的连续性聚合值 X Y 以及 theta
but because in A* we tend to expand
但是因为在 A* 里 我们倾向于沿着最短路径扩展单元格
cells along the shortest path before we look the longer paths,
然后我们才会选择更长点的路径
we not just cut this off and never consider to stay over here again.
我们不但会把这个排除 并且永远不会考虑回到这里
Now, this leads to a lack of completeness which
现在 这导致了完整性损失
means there might be solutions to
意味着这里或许有解
the navigation problem that this algorithm doesn't capture.
但是本算法并没有去处理
But it does give us correctness.
但是算法为我们保证了 合理性
So as long as our motion equations are correct,
所以 只要我们的运行方程是正确的
the resulting paths can be executed.
结果路径便是可行驶的
Now, here's a caveat.
这里 有个警告
This is an approximation and it's only correct
这是一个近似值
to the point that these motions equations are correct or not correct.
只在判断这些运动方程正确或者不正确时有效
But nevertheless, all paths that come out are nice,
但是无论如何 所有得出的路径都是相当不错的
smooth, and curved paths.
相当平滑 没有急转弯
And every time we expand the grid cell,
然后每次我们扩展单元格
we memorize explicitly the continuous values of X prime,
我们会明确保留
Y prime and theta with this grid cell.
与此单元格相关的 X’ Y’ 以及 theta 的连续值